

Boston, MA

📳 (+1) 978-201-5748 | 💌 robbenzmann@gmail.com | 😭 robbmann.io | 🖸 renzmann | 🛅 renzmann

Summary _

Sr. Data Scientist with a track record of empowering data science teams to do more, run faster, and build robust software. I specialize in the gap between business analytics and deployment engineering to help both teams work better together.

Work Experience _____

Algorex Health Technologies

Boston, MA

SR. DATA SCIENTIST Mar. 2021 - Present

- Led a company-wide transition to AWS SageMaker on more than a dozen client accounts, saving \$40,000 annually in infrastructure costs and reduced the onboarding time for new analysts from three days to 15 minutes. (Docker, Terraform, Jenkins)
- · Principal developer of the internal python software development kit, which optimized the engineering environment installation time from 45 minutes to 30 seconds. (Bash, Make, poetry)

Antuit, Inc. Frisco, TX

DATA SCIENTIST

Sep. 2017 - Mar. 2021

- · Built a custom simulation and nonlinear optimization application for strategic pricing of consumer healthcare products. (Python, Numpy, nlopt)
- · Wrote the ETL pipelines that translated client data into an analytics ready data warehouse that also fed back to a client-facing trade promotion optimization web application. (Spark, Kubernetes, Argo, Azure)
- · Derived MY2021 MSRP recommendations for an international motorcycle company. (Databricks, hyperopt)
- Modeled contractor costs for a warehouse trust fund and deployed the model/report into our client's infrastructure. (Denodo, Excel, Python)
- · Modeled personalization, customer churn, and lifetime value (CLTV) for a membership program with over 1MM members. (R)

Core Skills

Tools & Languages

I DABBLE IN MANY OTHERS - BUT THESE ARE MY BREAD & BUTTER

- Python, SSH, Git 5 yoe; specializing in DS with pandas, numpy, matplotlib; modeling experience with xgboost, scikit-learn, and hyperopt
- GNU/Unix, Bash, Make, SQL, Dask, Spark 3 yoe
- · AWS Athena (Presto SQL), PostgreSQL, SQLite 2 yoe

Tech Stack

WHERE AND HOW I'VE DEPLOYED THINGS

- · Azure, AWS 2 voe
- Databricks, SageMaker, Docker, Terraform

Education

Miami University Oxford, OH

Sep. 2015 - May 2017

- Master's topic: The Container Method for Triangle-induced Hypergraphs
- · 2017 Journal award

MASTER (M.A.) IN MATHEMATICS

Miami University Oxford, OH

Sep. 2013 - May 2015 B.A. IN MATHEMATICS

• Presented The (ab)surd Golden Ratio at TEDX Miami University on the false connections between art and the fibonacci sequence: https: //youtu.be/0vVxL60YFJU (over 325k views)

Miami University Oxford, OH

B.A. IN MUSIC

Sep. 2011 - May 2015

- 4-year music scholarship.
- · Focus in music technology, recording, and audio acoustic design.

APRIL 18, 2022 ROBERT ENZMANN · RÉSUMÉ